Claude agent SDK was sizzle number one.
But I have another sizzle lined up for
you and it's to show you co-work.
Co-work is another product by Claude by
Anthropic and it is basically taking
Claude code and that whole agentic
experience that that we tech people get
to to have and offering it to business
people or to anyone anyone that wants to
use Claude codes magic for things other
than coding. That's what coowork is
about. Claude coowwork. And I want to
show it to you now. And this is still
like an early release of it in research
preview. And maybe by the time you're
seeing this, it's already gone through a
few iterations. So you might be more
familiar with it. But let's do a quick
sizzle. Let's have a look at it. You
start by going to
claude.com/rouct/ccowork
link in the resources and then you
download Claude to install it on your
Mac or Windows box. and I'll see you
when you have it installed. And of
course, this is just the usual Claude
desktop app, which you may already have.
Uh if you don't, then the first time you
open it, it will look like this. Claude
for Mac for me and maybe Claude for Mac
for you, maybe Claude for Windows.
Fastest way to talk with Claude. I'm
going to press get started. It's going
to want me to log in. I'm going to come
in here. I'm going to continue with
Google. That's my Google account.
Continue.
And then back we come. And we're signed
on the usual oorthth flow. And then I
will just say it's it's giving me the
the um the instructions that that allow
me to have shortcut keys. And here we
are in something that looks very similar
to the web interface and is in fact of
course the desktop app. We are on chat
which is the normal way that you might
chat with Claude like claude.ai. But
you'll see there are some other tabs
here. It's worth pointing out there is
of course a a a code tab which looks
I'll make this nice and bigger which
looks very much like the one that that
was that was using uh Claude Cove on the
web looked like and it is of course also
going to be connecting to to the the
managed service of Claude on the web. Uh
and then there is co-work tab in the
middle. Let's knock something off your
list. Setting up Claude's workspace. So
again, what we're doing here is we are
connecting to Claude running on the
cloud for it to do a task for us. And
you can see that that it's got some some
things that it can do like optimize my
week, organize my screenshots. Uh it's
the the sorts of things that it's good
at doing. It's like Claude codes kind of
to-do list and abilities, but applied to
to everyday kinds of task. So the sorts
of things that co-work can do is stuff
like reorganizing files like it can look
at images. It can do stuff. It's also
got the ability to have plugins
customized with plugins. And you can see
from the way this is organized the
anthropic official plugins and so on.
There's like plug-in marketplaces. It's
all a very nice mirror from what we used
to with Claude Code. And this has stuff
like like looking digging through data,
looking at finance stuff, legal things
like contract review. we know a tool
that can that can build legal documents.
Uh NDA triage. Uh so there's lots of
useful things in here. Let's go for
something that might be useful for me
right now. Okay. So I'm going to click
on this button, work in a folder right
here. And I'm going to go into my
desktop. And there's a folder called
receipts. And I'm going to work in this
folder. Allow it to change files in
there. And now um in the folder that
I've shared with you
there are a bunch of receipts.
They are all PDFs of images. Please
uh review these and make me an expenses
report as an Excel file. Expenses
XLSX.
And that's what we will do. That would
be handy. There's like 12 of them in
there. It would like to access it. We'll
give it access to that. And off it goes.
There's stuff happening over here. Let
me start by reading the Excel skill and
checking what receipts you have. Off it
goes. Things are happening. 12 PDF
receipts. Let me read them all to
extract the details. So, we will let
this happen. Look at all these things
going on. Stuff happening there. Uh, and
uh, it's going through and reading them
at one at a time. And I will see you in
a minute when it's hopefully done. Well,
a lot happened there. It chugged away.
It did lots of processing. It had some
problems with the PDFs cuz it realized
it needed to read them in like images
and it did some stuff but it's just
finished after I think about five or 10
minutes of thinking. And in my receipts
folder a new file has appeared called
expenses.xlsx.
And if I launch that, this thing comes
up. And sure enough, it has like it's a
nicely formatted expenses report with 12
12 receipts in there and with all of
these different bits of visual audio
equipment and subscriptions and then
with a total and a total amount and it
all seems to be good. Uh and so yes,
that is something that that uh I might
have had to have done myself. It's from
the past. So I did that myself and so I
know that it's painful and this is an
example of the kind of task that is
quite easy for co-work. So there you
have it. This is taking the clawed code
that we know and that is so helpful for
us as engineers and allowing people to
use it for everyday tasks like making
expenses spreadsheets. This